



Jessica Claire

Skilled Technical Writer/Web Content Developer with a BA in English Secondary Teacher Credential Preparation, an AAS in Electronics, and over 15 years of experience supporting Customer Service, R&D, QA, and Software engineering departments for the following industries: Medical Instrumentation, UI/UX Software Development, IT, Telecommunications, Academic, Aerospace, and Defense.

Core Qualifications

- Platforms
- MS Win XP/Windows 7/Windows 8/Windows 10/iOS 8/iOS 9
- Programming Languages, Content Management Systems, and Front-End Frameworks
- HTML 5/XHTML 4.0/CSS, C, PHP, MySQL, Visual Basic, VBA, JQuery, Jason, Ajax, JavaScript
- Drupal and WordPress, Bootstrap and Foundation 5.0, GitHub
- Desktop Publishing, Office Applications, and Design Tools
- MadCap Flare 12, Adobe FrameMaker, RoboHelp, Photoshop, InDesign, Acrobat, MS Office Suite
- 2010/2013: Word, Excel, Access, and PowerPoint software; Paint, Snaglt Screen Capture, PSpice,
- LabVIEW, Orcad Capture/Layout 9.0, Visio software, Google Docs/Drive, SharePoint, and Citrix Page 1 of 2
- Jessica Claire
- Academic, FDA, and QA Standards and Communications Protocols
- Section 508 Standards, ANSIZ540A, NHB 5300.4, MIL STD 45622A, 981B, 1472D, and STD 1522A, ISO
- 9000/9001/9002, and SEMI S2, FDA & GMP compliance, WLAN IEEE 802.11n, WIMAX IEEE 802.16

Professional Experience

01/2014 to 01/2015 Technical Writer/Web Content Developer Harris Computer Systems | Newnan, GA,

- Provider of custom software development and user experience (UX) design for medical, touchscreen,.
- mobile, embedded, and desktop applications.
- Documented GUI software/hardware features on mobile, embedded, and desktop devices, medical.
- instrumentation, and HMI software Supported ICS's software engineers in a remote, Agile engineering environment using Citrix GoToMeeting, Skype, GitHub, Google Drive, and Google Docs.

01/2013 to 01/2014 Technical Writer/Web Content Developer SRJC Santa Rosa Junior College | City, STATE,

- Developed web content for Santa Rosa Junior College's website using Dreamweaver CC, Foundation 5 Responsive Front-End framework, and the Drupal Content Management System
- Created interactive web content using HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, and MySQL languages Documented academic software and developed the following training material: PowerPoint presentations, test procedures, and Quick Start Guides using Photoshop, MS Word, and PowerPoint.

01/2007 to 01/2008 Technical Writer/Training Specialist Agilent Technologies | City, STATE,

- Test & Measurement equipment for wireless telecommunications and mobile devices.
- Developed online help systems, test procedures, Quick Start Guides, FAQs, and maintenance and.
- operation manuals using Adobe RoboHelp, FrameMaker, Photoshop, Acrobat, and MS Word Interviewed SMEs; researched technical data; interfaced with Software, Hardware, and Mechanical Engineering, Customer Service, IT, and NPI departments.

01/2005 to 01/2006 Technical Writer/Instructional Designer Brooks Automation | City, STATE,

- Automation solutions for semiconductor manufacturing, life science drug discovery, and biobanking.
- Developed a 6-course Train-the-Trainer seminar, PowerPoint presentations, test procedures, SOPs,.
- and operation manuals using FrameMaker, Photoshop, MS Word, and PowerPoint software.

Education

Expected in 2004 to to BA | English Sonoma State University, Rohnert Park, CA GPA:

English

Expected in 1988 to to AAS | Electronics Engineering Technology Central NE College, Westborough, MA GPA:

Electronics Engineering Technology

Work History

to Information Technology department | ,

Accomplishments

- Documented academic software and developed web content for Santa Rosa Junior College's website using Dreamweaver CC, Foundation 5 Responsive Front-End framework, and the Drupal Content Management System.
- Developed five sections of an online help system for Agilent Technologies' Customer Education Department website using RoboHelp and FrameMaker applications.
- Web content included: software/hardware documentation of the GUI on Agilent's MIMO-based test equipment: The PXB Baseband Generator (for testing WiMAX, Cellular, and 3 GPP LTE devices) Created a six-course training seminar on HVAC-based electronic systems for Customer Service Engineers.
- Training package included: SOPs, maintenance and test procedures, online training material, and a PowerPoint presentation.
- Developed ISO9001/JPL compliant test procedures for Lockheed Martin's Atmospheric Infrared Sounder (AIRS), installed on the Aqua satellite in NASA's Earth Observing System.

Skills

Academic, Acrobat, Adobe, Dreamweaver, Photoshop, Agile, Ajax, Automation, C, Citrix, Communications Protocols, Hardware, Content Management, CSS, Customer Service, Desktop Publishing, Drupal, features, FrameMaker, Adobe FrameMaker, GMP, GUI, UX, HTML 5, HTML 5, PHP, InDesign, ISO 9000, JavaScript, JQuery, LabVIEW, Layout 9.0, Mechanical Engineering, Access, Excel, Office Applications, MS Office Suite, PowerPoint presentations, PowerPoint presentations, SharePoint, Windows 7, Windows 8, Win, Windows, Word, MS Word, Jessica, MySQL, online help, Orcad, Paint, Programming, PSpice, QA, Quick, RoboHelp, software development, Trainer, training material, Visio, Visual Basic, VBA, website, web content, wireless telecommunications, XHTML 4.0 Additional Information

• AWARDS AND PROFESSIONAL SOCIETIES Who's Who Among Young American Professionals 1988 Dean's List, Magna Cum Laude, Phi Theta Kappa Society 1988 Page 2 of 2 Jessica Claire